<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<PropertyList>
	<help>
		<title>Camel 1F1 - JSBSim</title>
		<key>
			<name>s</name>
			<desc>Start</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>b (or press brakes)</name>
			<desc>blip switch - both magnetos OFF </desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>B</name>
			<desc>toggle chocks</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>{ }</name>
			<desc>toggle left/right magneto switch</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>u/U</name>
			<desc>adjust pilot viewpoint up/down</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>ctrl u</name>
			<desc>select default pilot viewpoint </desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>e</name>
			<desc>fire guns </desc>
			
		</key>
    <key>
			<name>l</name>
			<desc>Change livery</desc>
			
		</key>
		<line> </line>
		<line>Starting</line>
		
		<line>Press { and } once each--so that both L and R magneto switches are in center position.</line>
		<line>Press and hold the s key for 1.5 seconds. It may take several tries before the engine catches.</line> 
		<line> </line>
		<line>Take Off</line>
		
		<line>Zoom the view out so you can see the edges of the runway with your peripheral vision.  As you roll out,</line>
		<line> you will need just a hair of left rudder to stay on the runway. As the tail lifts off the ground, about</line>
		
		<line>45 MPH, the torque of the engine will twist you counter-clockwise--you need a bit of right rudder and right</line>
		
    <line>aileron to counter the effect and keep moving in the straight line. </line>
    <line>Once you are rolling at 50 mph ease the stick back gently to lift off.</line>

    <line> </line>
    <line>The blip switch and magnetos </line>
    
		<line>The blip switch (b) disengages both magnetos and cuts power.</line>
		<line>Engaging either R or L brake (via keyboard, joystick, or rudder/pedals)</line>
    <line>also engages the blip switch.  Releasing the brake (or releasing the b key)</line>
    <line>releases the blip switch. Engaging only one magneto ({ or })reduces power.</line>
    <line>Negative G - Inverted flight </line>
    
		<line>The Camel's fuel system requires gravity to feed fuel to the engine.  If you fly inverted or otherwise pull</line>
		<line> negative Gs, the engine will run out of fuel after a few seconds.  Once you return to upright flight/</line>
    
    <line>positive Gs the engine will restart after a few seconds.</line>
    
		<line> </line>
		<line>Approach and landing</line>
		
		<line>Speed 55 MPH (48 KTS) IAS</line>
		<line>Throttle OPEN</line>
		<line>Use the blip switch/magnetos to control speed NOT throttle</line>
		<line>Blip switch ON/OFF as required</line>
		<line>Touchdown speed: 50-55 MPH (43-48 KTS) IAS</line>
		<line>Stall speed 48 MPH (41 KTS)) IAS</line>
		<line> </line>
		<line>Guns</line>
		
		<line>Guns have 400 rounds each, the maximum capacity of the Camel.</line>
	  <line>Note that guns will not work if AI models are disabled (the bullets</line> 
    <line>and smoke are AI objects - tracer rounds will appear but they won't move).</line>
    <line>Fire with the e key or a joystick trigger linked to /controls/armament/trigger. </line>
    <line>Reload guns: Use the menu--you must be on ground and stopped. </line>
    
	</help>
</PropertyList>
