<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<PropertyList>
	<help>
		<title>Camel 1F1 - JSBSim</title>
		<key>
			<name>s</name>
			<desc>Start engine (OR: Click propeller/center of dash)</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>b (or press brakes)</name>
			<desc>Blip switch - both magnetos OFF - blip and magnetos are the primary method for controlling engine power </desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>{ }</name>
			<desc>Toggle left/right magneto switch.  Magneto switches visible on dash at lower left.</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>B</name>
			<desc>Toggle chocks (OR: click chocks/wheels with mouse)</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>u/U/ctrl u</name>
			<desc>Adjust pilot viewpoint up/down, select default pilot viewpoint</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>m/M</name>
			<desc>Adjust mixture (If manual mixture selected via menu Camel/Toggle Manual Mixture) </desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>e</name>
			<desc>Fire guns </desc>
			
		</key>
    <key>
			<name>l</name>
			<desc>Change livery</desc>
			
		</key>
   <key>
			<name>n</name>
			<desc>Nudge aircraft forward (ie, when taxiing in the grass and stuck)</desc>
			
		</key>
      
    <key>
			<name>wasdqWASDQ and mouse</name>
			<desc>In INSPECT AIRCRAFT VIEW:  Move and look around (v/V to select this view; see View/View Options)</desc>
			
		</key>
    <key>
			<name>Camel Menu</name>
			<desc>Repair/restore aircraft (must be on ground/stopped), hide pilot and cockpit clutter, more</desc>
			
		</key>   
		<line> </line>
		<line>STARTING OUT</line>
		
		<line>Press { and } once each--so that both L and R magneto switches are in center position.</line>
		<line>Press and hold the 's' key for 1.5 seconds. It may take several tries before the engine catches.</line>
    <line>If you spawn in on the ground, chocks are in place. Shift-B to remove.  </line> 
		<line> </line>
   
		<line>TAKE OFF</line>		
		<line>Zoom the view out so you can see the edges of the runway with your peripheral vision.  </line>
		<line>Easiest, most dependable way to take off: Full throttle, moderate back-pressure on stick to keep </line>
		<line>tail engaged w/ ground. Use rudder to steer (tail dragging on ground provides most control authority).</line>
		<line>3-point lift-off @ 35 KTS (40 mph); immediately ease stick forward to avoid excessive climb and loss of airspeed.</line>
    <line>More advanced: Gently lift tail @ 35KTS and continue rolling (or in ground effect) through 45-50 KTS before lift-off.</line>
    <line>Crashing on takeoff? Check weather--many real Camel pilots crashed on take-off with strong crosswind or tailwind.</line>
    <line> </line>
    
    <line>THROTTLE, BLIP SWITCH, AND MAGNETOS</line>    
		<line>Real Camel pilots used a combination of throttle, magneto settings, and the blip switch to achieve desired power</line>
    <line>settings. Throttle provides a limited range of power settings. The blip switch (b) disengages both magnetos and cuts</line>
    <line>power totally. Engaging either R or L brake (via keyboard, joystick, or rudder/pedals) also engages the blip switch.</line>
    <line>Releasing the brake (or releasing the 'b' key) releases the blip switch. Engaging only one magneto ('{' or '}') </line> 
    <line>reduces engine RPM to just under half (L magneto) and just over half (F magneto).</line>
    <line>This gives you 3 distinct power settings via magneto (L, R, or both)--you can fine-tune each of them with the throttle.</line>
    <line>Note that L magneto ON/R magneto OFF + Blip switch gives you very fine low-power control for, e.g., approach and landing.</line>        
    <line></line>
    
    <line>NEGATIVE G - INVERTED FLIGHT</line>
		<line>The Camel's fuel system requires gravity to feed fuel to the engine.  If you fly inverted or pull negative Gs, the</line>
		<line>engine will soon stop.  Once you return to upright flight, fuel will flow and the engine will start again.</line>
		<line> </line>
   
		<line>APPROACH AND LANDING</line>	
		<line>Throttle HALF TO FULL OPEN, Magneto 1 ON, Magneto 2 OFF. Control engine power via Blip Switch (b); Engine is typically mostly OFF</line>
    <line>(via Blip) on approach. Note relatively steep glide slope. Sideslip as needed to control speed. If you need emergency full power,</line>
    <line>add Magneto 2 and throttle.</line>
		<line>Approach speed 55 KTS (63 mph) : Threshhold speed 48 KTS (55 mph) : Touchdown speed: 35 KTS (40 mph) (all IAS)</line>    
		<line>Stall speed: 31 KTS (35 mph) IAS</line>
		<line> </line>
   
		<line>GUNS</line>
		<line>Guns have 400 rounds each, the maximum capacity of the Camel.</line>
    <line>Fire with the 'e' key or a joystick trigger linked to /controls/armament/trigger. </line>
    <line>Reload guns: Use the menu--you must be on ground and stopped. </line>
   
    <line> </line> 
		<line>MISC </line>
    <line>Taxiing: In windy conditions, use elevator to hold tail firmly down for better steering authority. At high RPM, prop wash</line>
    <line>gives some rudder and elevator authority even at near stand-still. Use this plus the burst of power from Blip to</line>
    <line>help maneuver and taxi over bumps. Don't forget 'n' for nudge when you get stuck.</line>
    <line>Extensive help, tips, documents in the DOCS folder.</line>    
    
	</help>
</PropertyList>
