<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<PropertyList>
	<help>
		<title>Camel 1F1 - JSBSim</title>
		<key>
			<name>s</name>
			<desc>Start</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>b (or press brakes)</name>
			<desc>Blip switch - both magnetos OFF - this is the primary method for controlling engine power </desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>B</name>
			<desc>Toggle chocks</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>{ }</name>
			<desc>Toggle left/right magneto switch.  Magneto switches visible on dash at lower left.</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>u/U/ctrl u</name>
			<desc>Adjust pilot viewpoint up/down, select default pilot viewpoint</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>m/M</name>
			<desc>Adjust mixture (If manual mixture selected via Camel/Toggle Manual Mixture) (</desc>
		</key>
		<key>
			<name>e</name>
			<desc>Fire guns </desc>
			
		</key>
    <key>
			<name>l</name>
			<desc>Change livery</desc>
			
		</key>
   <key>
			<name>n</name>
			<desc>Nudge aircraft forward (ie, when taxiing in the grass and stuck)</desc>
			
		</key>
      
    <key>
			<name>wasdqWASDQ and mouse</name>
			<desc>In INSPECT AIRCRAFT VIEW:  Move and look around (v/V to select this view; see View/View Options)</desc>
			
		</key>
		<line> </line>
		<line>STARTING</line>
		
		<line>Press { and } once each--so that both L and R magneto switches are in center position.</line>
		<line>Press and hold the s key for 1.5 seconds. It may take several tries before the engine catches.</line> 
		<line> </line>
		<line>TAKE OFF</line>
		
		<line>Zoom the view out so you can see the edges of the runway with your peripheral vision.  </line>
		<line>Easiest, most dependable way to take off: Full throttle, moderate back-pressure on stick to keep </line>
		<line>tail engaged w/ ground. Use rudder to steer (tail dragging on ground provides most control authority).</line>
		<line> 3-point lift-off @ 35 KTS; immediately ease stick forward to avoid excessive climb and loss of airspeed.</line>
    <line>More advanced: Gently lift tail @ 35KTS and continue rolling (or in ground effect) through 45-50 KTs before lift-off.</line>
    <line>Crashing on takeoff? Check weather--many real Camel pilots crashed taking off with strong crosswind or tailwind.</line>
    <line> </line>
    <line>THROTTLE, BLIP SWITCH, AND MAGNETOS</line>
    
		<line>Real Camel pilots used a combination throttle, magneto settings, and the blip switch to  achieve desired power</line>
    <line>settings. Throttle provides a limited range of power settings. The blip switch (b) disengages both magnetos and cuts</line>
    <line>power totally. Engaging either R or L brake (via keyboard, joystick, or rudder/pedals)</line>
    <line>also engages the blip switch.  Releasing the brake (or releasing the b key)</line>
    <line>releases the blip switch. Engaging only one magneto ({ or })reduces power by about 1/3.</line>
    <line></line>
    
    <line>NEGATIVE G - INVERTED FLIGHT</line>
    
		<line>The Camel's fuel system requires gravity to feed fuel to the engine.  If you fly inverted or pull negative Gs, the</line>
		<line> engine will soon stop.  Once you return to upright flight the engine will start again.</line>
    
		<line> </line>
		<line>APPROACH AND LANDING</line>
		
		<line>Approach speed 48 KTS IAS</line>
		<line>Throttle FULL CLOSED, Magneto 1 OFF, Magneto 2 ON, Blip (b) ON/OFF and sideslip as needed to control speed</line>
		<line>Touchdown speed: 43-48 KTS IAS</line>
		<line>Stall speed: 41 KTS IAS</line>
		<line> </line>
		<line>GUNS</line>
		
		<line>Guns have 400 rounds each, the maximum capacity of the Camel.</line>
	  <line>Note that guns will not work if AI models are disabled (the bullets</line> 
    <line>and smoke are AI objects - tracer rounds will appear but they won't move).</line>
    <line>Fire with the e key or a joystick trigger linked to /controls/armament/trigger. </line>
    <line>Reload guns: Use the menu--you must be on ground and stopped. </line>
    
		<line>MORE HELP </line>
		<line>Extensive help, tips, documents in the DOCS folder.</line>    
    
	</help>
</PropertyList>
